Referee,
why don't you stop the fight?
Let's go!
Come on! Get him!
Come on! Hit him!
Hit him!
You're Waltzing.
Give the sucker some action.
You're fighting like a bum.
Want some advice?
Water.
Cold beer here!
Should I bet the fight don't go
three rounds? You feel strong?
- Absolutely.
- Cold beer!
- You want good advice?
- Mouthpiece.
Come on, Rock!
All right. All right.
Next a six-rounder
between local lightweights Kid Brooks
and Sugar Johnson.
Good going, champ.
- Hey.
- Say what?
- You got a smoke?
- Yeah, you can have this one.
You're a bum.
You're a bum, you know that?
You're a bum!
You really got lucky tonight.
Spider, here's loser's share.
$40, less $15 locker and cornerman,
$5 shower and towel, 7 percent tax.
Comes to 17.20.
You fought a good fight, Spider.
Balboa, you get winner's share, $65.
Less $15 locker and cornerman,
$5 shower and towel and 7% tax.
Comes to 40.55.
- When do I fight again?
- Maybe two weeks.
Give me a call. The doctor should be in
in about 20 minutes.
Hey, boy.
You guys are getting
better every year.
Yeah.
Hey, your old man did
pretty good tonight.
Why weren't you there?
You should've seen me.
You guys hungry?
Here you go.
You wanna see your
friend Moby Dick, huh?
How you doing, Moby Dick?
You miss me today?
Here you go. Say hi.
If you guys could sing or dance,
I wouldn't be doing this.
And this turtle food
I got here, it's...
This turtle food I got here
has more flies in it...
There are more moths
in it than flies.
More flies... More moths...
Who the hell cares?
How you feeling this morning?
Full of life?
Fine.
How you doing, killer?
- How's the turtle food this week?
- Fine.
I'm kind of aggravated.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Ain't your fault.
You don't wanna hear about it?
I'll tell you somebody
who don't wanna hear about it.
- How you doing, Gloria?
- Good.
The last turtle food I got here had
more moths in it than flies, Adrian.
These moths get caught
in the turtle's throat
and they cough, and I gotta smack
them on the back of the shell
and what do you think they get?
They get what?
Come on.
Shell shock.
They get shell-shocked.
What do you think?
You're starting with
the bad jokes early, huh?
Well, no. Inventing jokes
ain't so easy sometimes.
No, that wasn't no joke.
Hey, how's my buddy doing today?
Yo, Butkus.
Yo, Butkus!
What is it?
Hey, give me a kiss.
Adrian, go downstairs and clean
all the cat cages. They're a mess.
You gotta pay for that
turtle food, rock head.
Hey, crime don't pay.
You know that, Gloria.
- Yo, Rock, how's your boss?
- Real good.
Hey, Rock, you fighting again?
- Here and there.
- We'll make some money real soon, huh?
Yeah, a million dollars.
Hey, you. Where are you going?
Where are you going?
Where you running?
- Where you running?
- Hey! Hey!
- Hey! Don't hit the face!
- Shut up!
- Not the face!
- Mr. Gazzo wants the 200 now.
I'm broke!
Mr. Gazzo says I should get the 200
or break your thumb. You understand?
- Please, don't...
- What's your name again?
- Bob!
- Bob. Listen, Bob.
You wanna dance, you gotta
pay the band. You understand?
You wanna borrow,
you gotta pay the man.
Hey, I ain't emotionally involved, Bob.
You understand?
Give me some money.
There's 130 here.
That's it. I'm broke.
Hey, Bob, you're still $70 light.
You don't have to break nothing.
Take my coat.
It's worth $50, $60.
Take the coat!
You know, you should've
planned ahead.
You know that?
You should've planned ahead.
We'll fake it. I'll tape up the hand
like you broke the thumb!
- Should've planned ahead.
- Gazzo don't have to know!
He won't be wise to nothing!
Gazzo won't be wise to nothing!
Keep the coat! Keep the...
He only had 130, but I think he's good
for the rest next week, Mr. Gazzo.
Sure, Rocky. Bob's good for it.
That's it for today.
Tomorrow collect from Del Rio.
He's late three weeks. I don't like it.
Tomorrow, three weeks. Del Rio?
All right, I got it.
How do you spell Del Rio?
- How'd you do last night?
- I did real good.
- Hey.
- What?
- Did you get the license number?
- Of what?
The truck that run over your face.
Relax, Buddy.
Pull it over here.
I wanna let Rocky out.
I'm gonna talk to him for a few seconds.
Why didn't you break
this guy's thumb?
- How do you know I didn't?
- You don't think I hear things?
Didn't I give you
a job this morning?
- Yeah.
- Why didn't you break his thumb?
When you don't do what I tell you
to do, you make me look bad.
I figured... Look. I figured
if I break the guy's thumb,
he gets laid off.
- He can't make money.
- Let me do the figuring.
From here on in,
let me do the figuring.
These guys think we're running
a charity, they'll get off light.
From here on in,
do what I tell you to do,
because it's bad for my reputation.
You understand?
You got it, Rock?
I got it.
How do you spell Del Rio?
- Look it up in a dictionary.
- Come on!
I won't let that happen
no more, about the thumb.
You know?
So long, meat bag.
I should've broke your thumbs!
Hey, Rock.
Heard you did good last night.
- Absolutely. Should've seen me.
- Shouldn't you take a rest?
- No, my back is hurt.
- Your back?
My back is hurt.
You deaf?
No, I'm short.
Hey, yo, Mike.
Where's my lock?
Whose stuff is this in my locker?
It's Dipper's stuff.
It ain't your locker no more.
What you talking about?
It's been my locker for six years.
Where's my gear?
Mickey told me to
bag it and hang it.
You put my stuff on skid row.
I been in that locker for six years,
and you put my stuff on skid row?
Mickey tells me what to do,
I gotta do it.
Where is he?
He's outside working with Dipper.
- He's in a bad mood.
- So am I.
Keep your hands up.
Keep your hands up. Watch the right.
- Hey, Mick.
- Shut up!
To the body. Attaboy.
Time. Time!
What do you want?
- How you feeling today?
- What?
- How you feeling?
- Are you a doctor?
- You have problems today?
- Never mind. What's your problem?
I been talking to Michael.
How come I been put out of my locker?
Because Dipper needed it.
Dipper's a contender.
He's a climber.
Do you know what you are?
- You're a tomato.
- Tomato?
I run a business here,
not a goddamn soup kitchen.
- Did you fight last night?
- Yeah.
- Did you win?
- Yeah, I won K.O. in the second.
Yeah? Who'd you fight?
Spider Rico.
He's a bum!
- You think everybody I fight is a bum.
- Well, ain't they?
You got heart,
but you fight like a goddamn ape.
The only thing special about you,
you never got your nose busted.
Leave it that way. Nice and pretty
and what's left of your mind.
I think I'm gonna go take a steam.
You know why?
Because I did good last night,
and you should've seen me.
- Big deal.
- You should've seen me too.
Hey, kid.
- You ever think about retiring?
- No.
- You think about it.
- Yeah.
All right, time.
- Time!
- What?
I dig your locker, man.
Dig your locker.
Attaboy.
Cold night.
Whew! Good night to catch
pneumonia, you know?
You need some help?
There's a good game
at the Spectrum tonight.
You wanna go to a basketball game?
Hi, Butkus.
Hi, kid.
Tough day today.
They took my locker away.
I had that locker for six years.
It don't bother me.
Lockers are bad,
anyway, after a while.
People get the combination.
I must've had 20 bucks taken out
of there in the past 6 years.
Don't sound like much,
but it adds up.
Doesn't matter. Who cares?
Yeah, cold night. Hey, birds.
Hey, look who's here.
Look who's here.
The giant worm.
Look at these birds. Don't these
birds look like flying candy?
Bird, you wanna fly me home?
You need somebody to walk you home?
- No.
- No?
It's a cold night.
If you got the money, take a cab.
Too many creeps around here.
Every other block, there's a creep.
You can always tell a creep.
Listen. I'm gonna go now, okay?
I'll see you later, all right?
None of you guys get up. I know
you had a hard day in the cage.
So,
I'm gonna go home, make up a joke.
I'll tell you a new joke tomorrow.
Okay? Good night, Adrian.
Good night, Rocky.
Don't know what happened.
Hey, there, Lefty.
Got a friend for you here.
- Hello, Rock.
- How you doing?
- You seen Paulie?
- Yeah, he's in the steam room.
- Yeah.
- Hey, Rocky. What's with the eye?
- Been fighting.
- Hope you won it, at least.
Oh, yeah, did real good.
You should've seen me.
...heavyweight champion of the world
Apollo Creed at Kennedy Airport...
Hey, Rock, who'd you fight?
Spider Rico.
Jesus. Is he still around?
Yeah, he's doing real good.
He's doing better than you are.
Hey, Paulie. What, do you
look the door? Yo, Paulie.
I'd like to kill the freaking moron
who broke the mirror.
Hey, yo, Paulie.
Every day, every night, I pass by.
Your sister's giving me the shoulder.
- Forget her.
- What do you mean?
- You can do better than her.
- I don't forget nothing.
Every night I pass by, I tell a joke.
Every morning I pass by,
I tell a joke.
She just looks at me,
you know what I mean?
- Looks?
- Yeah, like I'm a plate of leftovers.
I need a Cadillac
to connect with your sister?
Something wrong with my face?
She's a freaking loser.
Sometimes she gets me so crazy,
I could split her head with a razor.
- Don't get mental.
- You caught me in a bad mood.
- You're always in a bad mood.
- Adrian ain't sharp.
Adrian is a loser.
She's pushing 30 freaking years old.
If she don't watch out,
she's gonna die alone.
- I'm 30 myself.
- And you'll die alone.
I don't see no crowd
around you neither.
I'd like to kill the freaking moron
who broke the mirror.
Come on.
Let's get out of this stink.
- I wanna talk to you anyway.
- About what?
- You still work for Gazzo?
- Yeah, sure.
Why don't you talk to
him about me?
I just don't think Gazzo's
hiring right now.
You know? Come on.
- The girl's dried up.
- Who?
My sister. If she don't start living,
her body's gonna dry up.
Tomorrow's Thanksgiving,
you know that?
- Come over and talk to her.
- Sure. Beer.
Tomorrow you come
for some bird, right?
Absolutely. You got it.
I gotta go. If I'm ten minutes late,
she calls the hospital.
- Paulie!
- I got it.
...Bicentennial fight with Mac Lee Green
here in Philadelphia
at the fabulous Spectrum.
Larry.
You're speaking now of your
much-publicized Bicentennial fight.
Right. This is gonna be the greatest
sporting event in the country's history.
A gala occurrence with me beating Green
like he committed a crime.
Would you take a look at that guy?
I mean, where are the real fighters
gonna come from? The pros.
All we got today are jig clowns.
...on January 1st. The first
major event in the country's...
- Clown?
- That's right, clown.
And in keeping with great events
throughout the country's history,
Apollo Creed will duplicate the cracking
of the Liberty Bell by cracking Green.
You're calling Apollo Creed a clown?
What else?
Look at him.
Stay in school and use your brain.
Be a doctor, be a lawyer,
carry a leather briefcase.
Forget about sports as a profession.
Sports make you grunt and smell.
- Be a thinker, not a stinker.
- Thanks a lot, champ.
You crazy?
This man is champion of the world.
He took his best shot
and become champ.
What shot did you ever take?
Hey, Rocky, you're not happy
with your life, that's nice.
But me, I got a business going.
I don't have to take no shots.
...no one having gone
more than 12 rounds with him...
- That's right.
- ...and that was Jake Dale last June...
- Stick that up your business.
- Why you getting so insulted?
You want me to take a shot?
All right.
I'll take a shot.
- Hey, Rocky, how about a bottle?
- No wine, man.
- Come on. Just a little.
- Buy us some Thunderbird.
Marie, does your brother know
you're hanging out so late?
- Get lost, creep.
- Screw you, yo-yo!
These guys teach you
to talk like that?
- Stuff it!
- Don't you never say that to me.
You stink up the neighborhood!
You know, you can...
When I was your age, only one girl in
the whole neighborhood talked like that.
That was it. Just one.
What are you doing? It'll make
your teeth yellow. Don't do that.
I like yellow teeth!
- It'll make your breath like garbage.
- Maybe I like garbage.
Nobody likes garbage.
Anyway, this girl with the dirty
mouth wasn't bad looking,
but none of the guys
ever took her serious.
They never took her out
for any serious date.
- Why?
- 'Cause that's the way guys are.
They laugh when you talk dirty.
They think you're cute.
After a while, you get a reputation.
You get no respect.
You understand? You get no respect.
I gotta use a bad word, whore.
You understand? Whore.
See? You use dirty words, and maybe
you end up becoming a whore.
Come on, Rocky.
I'm 12.
That don't matter.
You don't really have to be one.
Just act like one and that's it.
Boom! Bing! You get a bad rep.
You understand?
Twenty years from now,
people are gonna say,
"Do you remember Marie?"
"No. Who was she?"
"She was the little whore who hung
down at the Atomic Hoagie Shop."
"Oh, yeah. Now I remember her."
You see, they don't remember you.
They remember the rep.
You understand?
You got a boyfriend?
No, you ain't got a boyfriend.
You know why? Why don't you
think you have a boyfriend?
'Cause you're hanging out with them
coconuts on the corner.
You hang around coconuts,
you get nowhere.
They're lemons. Lemons.
You hang out with nice people,
you get nice friends. You understand?
You hang out with smart people,
you get smart friends.
You hang out with yo-yo people,
you get yo-yo friends.
You see, it's simple mathematics.
- I hope you ain't...
- I won't.
What was I gonna say?
You hope I don't keep acting like a
whore or I'll turn into one, right?
Yeah, something like that.
Good night, Rocky.
- Good night. Take care.
- Hey, Rocky.
- Yo.
- Screw you, creep-o!
Yeah, who are you to
give advice, creep-o?
Who are you?
- Are the doctor's reports confirmed?
- Definitely.
Says here Mac Lee
Green has suffered
"a severely cracked third
metacarpal in his left hand."
Damn!
We can cancel the fight indefinitely
if you're set on fighting Green.
Hey, it ain't just Green.
What about all the time
Apollo has invested?
We can find a solution.
Solution nothing.
Find me another ranked contender
in a flash, Jergens.
Don't play games with my client.
Apollo's already done a million
dollars' worth of publicity,
has made contractual obligations
with 20 different organizations.
He's not going to be embarrassed!
I contacted Ernie Roman's manager.
Ernie's fighting in
France that same week.
Then get me Buddy Shaw.
He's ranked fifth.
Went to California and
gained 50 pounds.
I called
every worthwhile contender.
They all say five weeks isn't
enough time to get into shape.
Shape nothing, man.
They're afraid.
They know everybody
is gonna see this fight.
None of them's got
a prayer of whipping me.
They're making excuses so they don't
have to be the chump who gets whipped.
All I can say is I'm
a good promoter.
I've promoted fights
in every goddamn country in the world
and I've broken my ass over this one.
I don't know what else to do!
I do.
Without a ranked contender,
what this fight needs is a novelty.
This is the land of
opportunity, right?
So, Apollo Creed,
on January 1st,
gives a local underdog fighter
an opportunity.
A snow-white underdog, and I'm gonna
put his face on this poster with me.
And I'll tell you why.
Because I'm sentimental.
A lot of other people in this country
are just as sentimental
and there's nothing they'd like
better than to see Apollo Creed
give a local Philadelphia boy a shot
at the greatest title in the world
on this country's biggest birthday.
Now that's the way I see it
and that's the way it's gonna be.
Apollo, I like it.
It's very American.
No, Jergens. It's very smart.
- What is it?
- I wanna check this thing out.
You said pick up two yards from Snyder
and a grand from Cappoli, right?
No, no. Two yards from Cappoli
and a grand from Snyder.
- Two yards.
- Write it down, okay?
Yeah, I got it.
Who's this girl you're going out with
tomorrow night?
- How'd you know?
- I know.
Don't you think I hear things? Lot
of canaries flying around the docks.
- I'm going out with Paulie's sister.
- Hey, Rocky.
- What?
- I hear she's retarded.
She ain't retarded.
She's shy, you know?
Tell you what to do. Take her to the zoo.
I hear retards like the zoo.
- This bum gotta say that?
- Who you calling a bum?
- Back it up, Buddy.
- I'm calling you a bum!
Relax, relax. Buddy's in a bad mood.
It's his prostate.
He's always in a bad mood.
You ought to count your blessings.
You're still a healthy person.
- I don't like your face.
- I don't like yours either!
- Kiss my ass!
- Come out here!
Relax! Relax. My ears.
Are you driving me crazy?
Both of you.
Look. Buddy doesn't like you.
Some guys, they just hate
for no reason. Capisce?
- Yeah.
- Come here.
Here's 50 bucks. You and your girl
Adrian, you have a nice time.
Thanks.
How'd you know her name?
You don't think I hear things?
Hey, Rock.
What?
- Remember what I told you?
- What'd you tell me?
Take her to the zoo.
Come on out of the car!
- Some more coffee, Mr. Creed?
- No, thanks, Shirley.
What do you think about Billy Snow?
Fouls.
How about Big Chuck Smith?
No, he's too old and dull.
Hey, that Bobby Judge,
he's a good boy.
No. I don't feel no
heat from that name.
Joe Zack's a good prospect.
Exactly what are you
looking for, Apollo?
This is what I'm looking for.
The Italian Stallion.
Rocky Balboa?
Never heard of him.
Look, it's the name, man.
The Italian Stallion.
The media will eat it up.
Who discovered America?
An Italian, right?
What would be better than to get
it on with one of his descendants?
He's a southpaw.
I don't want you messing around
with southpaws.
- They do everything backwards.
- Southpaw nothing.
I'll drop him in three.
Apollo Creed meets
the Italian Stallion.
Sounds like a damn monster movie.
What are you doing with that bat?
I used to be deadly
at stickball.
- Your sister knows I'm coming?
- She's very excited.
- Look at these swollen hands.
- Yeah.
The joints from carrying meat
in and out of the freezer.
- Plays hell on the joints.
- Maybe you ought to see a doctor.
I don't need a doctor.
I need a different job.
Different job. What kind of turkey?
Big? Small?
Talk to Gazzo.
Tell him I'm a good man.
Nothing bothers me.
I'd make a great collector.
Busting bones don't bother me.
Don't bother you. Big turkey, right?
Gazzo's gotta give me...
Forget Gazzo. It's a bad job.
You got a match?
Go to him for me.
As a favor.
Yeah, yeah.
Last time I had a turkey
was when they had a two-dollar special
at Horn and Hardart's three years ago.
Last year, me and the
turtles had Spam.
- Your sister knows I'm coming?
- Yeah, yeah. She's very excited.
Will you forget about Gazzo?
I don't ask nobody twice.
Don't ask nobody twice.
You're sure your sister
knows I'm coming?
Yeah. She's very excited.
Paulie, you're late.
You call the hospital?
She calls the hospital
if I'm ten minutes late.
Yo, how you doing?
I told you, she's very excited.
Why didn't you tell me
you were bringing him here?
I'm not ready for this.
Would it make
a difference if you were?
- He's taking you out.
- No, I can't.
I want you out of
the kitchen right now.
I won't.
I want you out of
here instamatically!
I'm sick of seeing you hanging
around like a freaking spider.
Go out and live. Enjoy life!
I can't go!
Don't get wise with me now.
I'm tired of you being a loser.
Don't call me that, Paulie!
Apollo Creed says
he'll be shopping for another victim
to fill Green's vacancy for the
Bicentennial championship fight...
Why didn't you tell me
you were bringing him home?
How do you know I didn't?
I can't go, Paulie. I won't go!
Why?
Paulie, it's Thanksgiving.
I got a turkey in the oven.
Oh, a turkey in the oven.
Turkey in the oven.
You want the bird?
Go in the alley and eat the bird!
Aw, Paulie!
I want you out of here!
Get out of the house!
Go out and enjoy your freaking life!
You hungry, Rock?
Hey, yo, Paulie, maybe we better
forget all this, you know?
Forget nothing. Go ahead.
Tell her something funny.
Ain't nothing to talk about.
She's in a bad mood. I'm in a bad mood.
You can do funny things.
You wanna go out with my sister?
- Yeah.
- Well...
I don't know what to say.
Funny.
Yo, Adrian. It's me, Rocky.
Rocky, you know?
Listen,
I don't know what to say, 'cause I ain't
never talked to no door before.
What do I say to a door?
We better forget this.
You're doing fine.
I ain't doing fine.
I look like an idiot.
Keep doing what you're doing. Funny.
I know all about these things.
I feel like a jerk.
Yo, Adrian, it's Rocky again.
Listen, I know you ain't too happy
at this moment.
But could you do me a favor?
I ain't got nobody
to spend Thanksgiving with.
So, how about maybe you and I
go out together,
get something to eat.
Maybe laugh a little bit.
Who knows, you know?
Would you like to...
Would you like to, maybe,
you and me go out together?
What do you think?
Would you like to?
We're gonna have a good time.
We'll have a real good time.
Thanks for the bird.
I'm gonna turn the TV off.
I got a headache.
- What's your sister like to do?
- Ice-skate.
Adrian, come on.
You're letting the heat out.
Who pays the bills around here?
Listen, I don't want no
turkey anyway, you know?
But it was Thanksgiving.
What?
- It was Thanksgiving.
- Yeah, to you.
But to me it's Thursday, right?
- It looks kind of quiet.
- I think it's closed.
No, I think we're just early
or something like that.
- We're closed.
- What?
- I said we're closed.
- Yeah. Hey, listen.
I'm gonna smooth this guy out.
Wait here. I'll be right back.
- We could go someplace else.
- No, it's okay.
Are you closed to the general public,
or are you just closed to everybody?
It's after 6:00. It's Thanksgiving.
That's why there's nobody here.
Besides, you ain't
supposed to be in here.
So do me a favor
and not stay here.
- Could you do me a favor?
- Come on. We're not operating.
Look. This girl here
ain't feeling well.
Doctors say she should go out
and exercise.
Ice-skating's probably
the best thing.
So what do you want from me?
Well, hey,
I want you to do me a favor.
You can see she ain't
feeling too good.
If you can let her on the ice
for a few minutes, I'd appreciate it.
Ten minutes, ten bucks.
Ten bucks?
How about eight bucks?
Come on. It's Thanksgiving.
All right.
Nine bucks, you got a deal.
You have the ice to yourself.
Ten bucks.
Give her the blades.
Aren't you skating?
No,
I ain't skated since I was 15.
That's when I started fighting.
Skating's kind of bad for
the ankles, you know?
You're a pretty good
skater, aren't you?
Like I was saying
before on the way over here,
fighting used to be tops with me,
but no more.
All I wanted to do out of fighting
was prove I was no bum,
that I had the stuff
to make a good pro.
- You never got the chance?
- I ain't crying about it.
I still fight. I do it like a hobby.
The trouble is I'm a southpaw.
- What's a southpaw?
- A southpaw means you're left-handed.
A southpaw throws
your timing off.
It throws other guys' timing off,
makes them look awkward.
Nobody wants to look awkward.
- You know where "southpaw" came from?
- Nine minutes!
A long time ago, there was this guy,
maybe a couple hundred years ago,
he was fighting in the...
I think it was around Philadelphia.
His arm... He was left-handed.
His arm was facing towards New Jersey.
And that's south. So naturally
they called him "south paw." You see?
Southpaw, South Jersey,
South Camden.
Southpaw.
You know what I mean?
Things probably worked out for
the best, don't you think?
Never got a chance
because you're left-handed, huh?
That's absolutely true,
you know?
Watch out.
Ah! Ah!
I just dislocated my finger.
Ah! Look at that.
Wait. It ain't your fault. Look.
See? I had it... It's an old wound.
You see that? Look. See?
Nothing. It bends like that.
I originally done it... Push the button.
Bong. It works.
- It ain't your fault. Look.
- Seven minutes!
I originally done it...
I carry pictures of all my fights.
I originally done it
in the Baby Crenshaw fight.
Baby's about the size of an
airplane. I broke both hands on his face.
I lost that fight, but that's a
nice picture, don't you think?
Real nice.
Come on. You having a good time?
You can see I ain't too graceful.
I don't move well, but I can really swat.
I can really hit hard.
But I'm a southpaw, and nobody
wants to fight no southpaw.
You know how I got
started in fighting?
No.
Am I talking too loud?
Three minutes!
My father, he's a...
My old man, he was never too smart.
He says to me, "You weren't
born with much of a brain,
"so you better start
using your body."
So I become a fighter.
You know what I mean?
Why you laughing?
My mother, she said
the opposite thing.
What did she say the opposite?
She said, "You weren't
born with much of a body,
"so you better develop your brain."
- Did she say that?
- Yo, time!
- Can I ask you a question?
- Absolutely.
- Why do you wanna fight?
- 'Cause I can't sing or dance.
Hey, yo.
Don't fall!
That was terrific.
I'm pretty good at this.
You like the way I skate?
Last fight I had, I had with
this guy named Spider Rico.
He busted my head up there.
You see that scar?
I'll tell you,
things get pretty rough in the ring.
You know,
some people are very shy by nature.
I suppose.
I say you're very shy
by nature, you know?
I suppose.
The bum from the dark.
Get a job, you bum!
Some people think
that being shy is a disease,
but it don't bother me none.
Don't bother me either.
So Why'd I bother bringing it up?
'Cause I'm dumb, that's why.
I think we make
a sharp couple of coconuts.
I'm dumb and you're shy.
What do you think?
I don't understand
why anybody would wanna be a fighter.
You gotta be a moron to wanna
be a fighter, you know what I mean?
It's a racket where you're
almost guaranteed to end up a bum.
- I don't think you're a bum.
- I'm at least half a bum.
But I'll tell you something.
Worst thing about fighting
is the morning after.
- You know?
- Morning after.
Yeah, the morning after a fight,
you're like a large wound,
you know what I mean?
Sometimes I got pains all over me.
I feel like calling a taxi to take me
from the bed into the bathroom.
Your hair hurts,
your eyes hurt.
Your face is busted up.
Your hands are swollen.
Look at this face. Sixty-four fights.
Look at that nose.
You see that nose?
That nose ain't never been broken.
I had guys busting on it.
I had guys chewing on it,
twisting and punching it.
I mean, whack, boom.
These guys are hitting my nose
all the time.
Never broke it.
I'm very proud of that.
That's rare.
- Why do you do it if it hurts?
- Why you think?
'Cause you can't
sing and dance?
Yeah, something like that.
Hey, you wanna come inside?
No, I gotta go.
Hey, come on.
I got some animals.
I got these very rare
animals inside.
Come on in.
No, I gotta go.
I gotta go, too,
to the bathroom. Come on.
Come on.
No, I gotta go.
Look at this face.
Is that a face you could trust or what?
Is it? They ought to stick this face
on a stamp. What do you think?
Come on in.
Yo, come on.
Click.
Yo, Adrian, you hungry?
No.
I got some things in there.
If you like sodas,
doughnuts or something.
Got a couple cupcakes.
Huh?
No?
I got some chocolate in there. No?
Hot in here, you know?
I could go for some music.
Yo, Adrian.
These are the exotic animals
I was telling you about.
These are my friends, Cuff and Link.
- I sold them to you.
- I know you sold them to me.
Remember you were working
at that pet shop?
First day you was there, and I came in
and bought both these animals?
I remember that.
I bought this bowl
and the animals themselves.
Some food, the marbles that
go on the bottom there.
Remember that mountain?
I had to get rid of that mountain.
They kept fall over and flipping.
Why don't you come over here
and sit down?
It's a nice couch. I don't know.
There's big bugs in there.
It's safer over here.
You wanna sit down?
These your parents?
Yeah, that's both of them there.
- Is this you?
- Yeah. I was eight years old.
That's the Italian Stallion
when he was a baby.
Come on over.
Make yourself comfortable. Relax.
Do you have a phone?
No, I had it pulled.
'Cause people calling all the time,
and who needs the aggravation, right?
Interruptions.
Who'd you wanna call?
I wanna let my brother
know where I am.
Why?
I think he might be worried.
I'll call your brother,
if that's the problem.
Yo, Paulie!
Your sister's with me!
I'll call you back later!
See you!
You don't like the room,
do you?
- It's fine.
- It's only temporary.
It's not that.
What's the problem?
You don't like me?
You don't like the turtles?
What's the problem?
- I don't think I belong here.
- It's okay.
I don't belong here.
Well, you know, it's okay,
'cause you're my guest.
I don't know you well enough.
I've never been
in a man's apartment alone.
Well, they're all
the same, you know?
I'm not sure I know you well enough.
I don't feel comfortable.
Yo, Adrian,
I ain't so comfortable either.
I should go.
Don't go, please. Don't go.
Don't go.
Do me a favor.
What?
Take off these glasses.
You have nice eyes, you know?
Do me another favor?
Why don't you take off that hat?
I always knew you was pretty.
- Don't tease me.
- I'm not teasing you.
I ain't teasing you.
I just wanna...
I wanna kiss you.
You don't have to kiss me back
if you don't wanna,
but I wanna kiss you.
- Heard you had a fight coming up.
- Next month.
January 27, right?
That's good. Come down to the gym.
We'll get you in shape.
How's your weight?
- 175.
- Hey, Rock. How you doing?
Mick was looking for
you up there, man.
- For me? You're sure?
- Yeah, yeah.
He's looking for you.
Get up there and see him.
- He wanted me?
- Yeah. Your name's Rock, right?
- Yeah.
- All right. Go on, babe.
You got something for me?
Yeah, there was some guy
from Miles Jergens looking for you.
They need sparring partners
for Apollo Creed. There's the card.
- When was he here?
- About an hour ago.
They're probably looking
for sparring partners for Creed.
I said that before,
you dumb Dago!
I been coming here for six years, and
six years you been sticking it to me.
- How come?
- You don't wanna know!
Yeah, I wanna know how come.
- You wanna know?
- I wanna know now!
Okay, I'm gonna tell you!
You had the talent to become
a good fighter, and instead of that,
you became a leg breaker
for some cheap, second-rate loan shark!
It's a living.
It's a waste of life!
Yes. May I help you?
Oh, you must be Mr. Rocky Balboa.
Mr. Jergens's expecting you.
Just a moment.
Mr. Rocky Balboa to see you, sir.
Fine.
- Please go in, Mr. Balboa.
- Can I have that?
- Oh, certainly.
- Thanks.
Mr. Balboa.
How are you?
George Jergens.
Take a chair, please.
Thanks.
Mr. Balboa.
Call me Rocky.
Rocky, you got any representation?
You have a manager?
No, just me.
Rocky, I've got a proposition
I'd like to make to you.
- About sparring?
- Beg your pardon?
I know you're looking for sparring
partners, and I'm very available.
- I'm sure you are.
- Absolutely.
Sparring with the champ
would be an honor,
and you know what, Mr. Jergens?
- What?
- I wouldn't take no cheap shots.
I'd really be a good
sparring partner.
You don't understand me, Rocky.
My proposition's this.
Would you be interested
in fighting Apollo Creed
for the world heavyweight
championship?
No.
Listen, Rocky.
Apollo's seen you fight.
He likes you.
He wants to fight you.
Well, it's just that, you see,
I fight in clubs, you know,
and I'm really a ham-and-egger.
This guy, he's the best, and
it wouldn't be such a good fight,
but thank you very much.
I appreciate it.
Rocky, do you believe that America
is the land of opportunity?
Yeah.
Apollo Creed does,
and he's gonna prove
it to the whole world
by giving an unknown
a shot at the title.
And that unknown is you.
He picked you, Rocky.
It's the chance of a lifetime.
You can't pass it by.
What do you say?
All right, fellas.
That's enough pictures.
We wanna ask Apollo a few questions.
Apollo, how do you like
the City of Brotherly Love?
Well, just being in
Philadelphia makes me feel patriotic.
Beautiful people in a beautiful city
coming up to me on the street,
wishing me the best.
I love my Philadelphia brothers,
and I'm proud to be an American.
Apollo? Champ?
Why did you agree to fight a man
who has virtually no chance of winning?
If history proves one thing,
American history proves that
everybody's got a chance to win.
Didn't you guys ever hear
of Valley Forge or Bunker Hill?
Apollo?
It is a coincidence
that you're fighting a white man
on the most celebrated day
in the country's history?
I don't know. Is it a coincidence
that he's fighting a black man
on the most celebrated day
in the country's history?
- Right on, Apollo!
- Tell the truth, brother!
Listen, Apollo. How
do you feel about your challenger?
How do I feel about him?
Come here, Rock.
My main man.
- Rocky, ain't you Italian?
- Yeah, I'm Italian.
Now what does that mean?
That means, if he can't fight,
I'll bet he can cook.
Do me a favor. His lungs, punch out.
Paulie.
Rocky, how do you expect
to fight Apollo Creed?
Oh, jeez, you know,
Creed's the best.
I guess I'll have to do
the best I can.
Tell me, Rocky, just between us,
where did you get
the name "Italian Stallion"?
Oh, I invented that about eight
years ago when I was eating dinner.
Rocky, now your payday
will be $150, 000.
Any comment?
- You got no comment, Rocky, right?
- No.
- Thank you, Rocky.
- Wait a minute.
I just wanna say hi to
my girlfriend, okay?
Yo, Adrian, it's me, Rocky.
You believe all this?
Microphones and all that stuff.
You didn't.
- Thank you, Rocky.
- Who you pushing, man?
- Smack you in the mouth!
- Thank you, Rocky.
Don't it matter he making
you out a fool?
I'd break his lips.
- He's taking cheap shots.
- Don't bother me none.
Yo, Rocky, I guess you'll be looking
for people to help you out.
Help what?
You know,
keep you living the clean life.
I do okay, you know.
You need someone
to help with the exercise
and someone standing by with a towel
or running errands?
Hey, yo, Paulie,
who cared about me yesterday? Nobody.
So I just think I'm gonna
train myself, you know?
Without such good people around
to help you,
you don't have such a good chance.
Einstein flunked out
of school twice.
That so?
Yeah. Beethoven was deaf.
Helen Keller was blind.
I think Rocky's got a good chance.
Want me to get you a beer, Paulie?
You looking to do a good deed?
Keep out of my freaking life!
- What'd I do?
- Nothing.
Did I say something wrong?
You didn't say nothing.
It's all right.
That's right!
You didn't say nothing!
Nothing at all!
I gotta go.
Where are the freaking pretzels?
I'd like to have a pretzel.
Hey, we ain't got any beer?
I thought you were supposed to
pick up some beer!
How'd you like hearing your name
on TV tonight?
I was shocked.
Why'd you do that?
You're putting me on, right?
Absolutely.
- What time should I expect you?
- About 7:00.
- Okay.
- Hey.
You know how I said
that stuff on TV didn't bother me?
Yeah.
It did.
Listen, the reason I brought
you here is because
I wanna know if you got any money
for training expenses.
I got a few dollars.
A few bucks? Here.
Put this in your glove.
- What's this?
- $500. Don't worry about it.
You know, you ain't
never had any luck,
but I think this time Lady Luck
may be in your corner.
- What do you think?
- Maybe.
Thanks for the money, Tony.
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
I'll see you.
- Wait a minute.
- What?
You're in training.
Come on.
- Yo, Tony.
- What?
You gonna show up at the fight?
Ringside.
I'll see you.
Yeah.
Hello, kid. I seen your light.
Can I come in?
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah. Good.
Hey, it's a nice place here.
Anyway, what I come
to tell you is that,
that what happened to
you is freak luck.
- Yeah, freak luck.
- Ain't it true?
Look at the other guys.
They're good fighters, right?
They're colorful.
They got good records.
They fight their guts
out for peanuts.
But you, you got
a shot at the title!
Freak luck is a strange thing,
you know?
- Sure is. Can I sit down?
- Yeah, sure.
- What the hell are those?
- Domestic turtles.
The one on the top is Cuff
and the other guy's Link.
The rest are marbles.
Yeah?
They make good soup.
Anyway.
Look, I'm here to warn you.
You gotta be very careful about this
shot that you got at the title.
Because, like the Bible says,
you ain't gonna get a second chance.
Yeah. All right.
You thought of that, huh?
Well, what you need is a manager.
A manager. Listen to me.
I know, because I been
in this racket for 50 years.
- 50 years, huh?
- 50 years. I've seen it all.
- All of it. You know what I done?
- What?
I have done it all.
You should've seen me when I knocked
Ginny Russell out of the ring.
Out of the goddamn ring, I tell you.
September 14, 1923,
and it was the same night that Firpo
knocks Dempsey out of the ring.
So who gets the publicity?
Figure that out.
- Dempsey.
- That's right. But why?
- 'Cause he was champ.
- No! Because he had a manager.
I had nothing.
I wanna show you something.
I want you to look at my face.
Look at this. I got 21
stitches over this left eye.
I got 34 stitches over this eye.
You know I had my
nose busted 17 times.
The last time
was in that fight with Sailor Mike.
I got that clipping here.
It was a good fight.
Wanna read that?
Well, it doesn't matter.
Anyway, he put this
vegetation on my ear.
You kind of remind me of the Rock,
you know that?
- You really think so?
- That's right.
You move like him,
and you got heart like he did.
Yeah, I got heart, but I ain't
got no locker, do I, Mick?
Anyway.
You know, when I begun
in this business, kid...
I wanna make a suggestion.
Don't drink that piss before a fight.
It's no good for you.
If you don't mind my saying.
Anyway, you know,
when I started in this racket,
pugs like us, we was
treated like dogs.
For $10, you got to
tear somebody's throat out.
But I never had no management.
One time, this son of a
bitch that I fought,
he put a nail right there.
- In his thumb.
- In the thumb of the glove.
He punched so many holes in my face,
I had spit shooting out of my cheeks.
Can you imagine that?
Anyway, when I tell you what I
looked like when I was in my prime.
I want you to look at something.
Look at that.
That's the way I looked
before these guys got at me.
That's nice. You didn't take very
good care of the picture, though.
Well, I never had no management.
That's the trouble,
but now I got all this knowledge.
I got it up here.
Now I wanna give it to you.
I wanna give you this knowledge.
I wanna take care of you.
I wanna make sure that what happened
to me doesn't happen to you.
You know what I mean?
Mick, the fight's set.
Listen to me.
I wanna be your manager.
You follow that?
Fight's set.
I don't need no manager.
But you can't buy
what I'm gonna give you.
I got pain and I got experience.
I got pain and I got experience too.
Listen, kid.
Hey, Mick.
I needed your help
about 10 years ago, right?
Ten years ago. You never helped me none.
You didn't care.
If you wanted help...
I say, if you wanted help,
why didn't you just ask me, kid?
I asked,
but you never heard nothing!
Well, I...
know I..
I'm 76 years old.
And...
Took you long enough to get here.
Took 10 years to
come to my house.
You don't like my house?
My house stink?
That's right, it stinks!
I didn't
ask no favors from you!
Talk about your prime.
What about my prime, Mick?
At least you had a prime!
I ain't had no prime.
I ain't had nothing.
Legs are going, everything is going.
Nobody's giving me nothing.
Guy comes up, offers me a fight.
Big deal.
Wanna fight the fight?
Yeah, I'll fight the big fight.
I'm gonna go fight that big fight
and I'm gonna get that!
I'm gonna get that!
And you wanna be
ringside and see?
Do you?
You wanna help me out?
Do you wanna see me
get my face kicked in?
Legs ain't working,
nothing's working.
Think I'll go and fight the champ.
Yeah, I'll fight him.
Get my face kicked in.
And you come around here.
You wanna move in with me?
Come on in.
It's a nice house!
Real nice! Come on in! It stinks!
This whole place stinks.
You wanna help me out?
Well, help me out! Come on.
Help me out. I'm standing here!
It's only about
28 degrees. We'll check that forecast.
I feel very mischievous,
very weird, very...
I got vinyl seats in my car.
When I hit those seats this morning,
I just went, "Whoo!"
I figure if I'm up, everybody
in the Delaware Valley should be up.
You agree with me?
At three minutes past 4:00 in
the morning, what else you gonna do?
Hello?
Good morning, Mrs. Kramer. This
is Don Cabot, VINBG Philadelphia?
- How are you this morning?
- What?
You have a lot of nerve calling
me at this hour of the morning!
Good-bye!
Me and Mrs. Kramer are up,
and it's a good morning.
I tell you, I need someone
to snuggle with. 28 degrees.
It's cold out there.
We deserve it.
We've been getting away with
murder the last couple of weeks.
Our high today could be...
Tonight we 're back down
in the 20-degree range.
A little colder in the suburbs.
Tomorrow, with a little bit of luck,
we may hit 40.
But it's 28.
It's awfully chilly.
Make sure you have it bundled up
before you bring it out.
Come on.
It stinks in here, you know?
Yeah. I know.
Did you kill all these things?
No, across the street.
It's like an animal morgue.
It's a little cold in here, ain't it?
Yeah.
Who killed all these things?
Are you crazy, Paulie?
If you don't pay Gazzo,
you end up on a hook.
Gazzo's a good man.
You know that.
Don't get excited.
I know that.
That's why I wanted you to talk to
him about me and the collecting job.
I can get me out of
this stinking freezer.
Why don't you do yourself a favor?
Keep this job. You eat better.
Moo.
Does it ever snow in here?
You and my sister,
how you getting along together?
How do you think?
I'm not sure, Rock.
What's the story?
About what?
What's happening?
You really like her?
Sure, I like her.
I don't see it.
What's the attraction?
I don't know.
Fills gaps, I guess.
What's "gaps"?
I don't know. She's got gaps.
I got gaps. Together we fill gaps.
You balling her?
Hey.
You don't talk dirty
about your sister.
Are you screwing my sister?
You see? That's why I can't
connect you with Gazzo.
Because you got a big mouth.
You just talk too much.
- It's cold in here. I'm going home.
- Cold in here?
It is cold in here!
It stinks in here,
and you stink!
You're breaking the ribs.
If you do that to Apollo Creed,
they'll put us in jail for murder.
I'll see you tomorrow
morning, okay?
- I turned the heat up.
- Thanks.
Your brother's a good man,
but he's awful pushy, you know?
- You want me to rub you down?
- No, I'm just sore, okay?
- I'm gonna just sit here.
- You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Hey, come on.
No fooling around, all right?
I'm tired.
Adrian, I'm serious now.
There's no fooling
around during training.
I wanna stay strong.
- You're not kidding.
- No, I ain't kidding.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
Why don't you just
make the meat, okay?
Okay, I'll make the meat.
- It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
Hey.
Underneath! Underneath!
Knock him out! Come on!
Hold it. Hold it, Rock!
You're driving me crazy. You're so
sloppy because you're off balance.
Let's try this. Take this string.
Tie it to both ankles.
- Leave about two feet of slack.
- I never had good footwork.
Never mind footwork.
Now you're all balanced.
Marciano had the same problem
and this string cured it.
If you can move and hit without
breaking the string, you got balance!
You become a dangerous person.
- You follow me?
- Looking good, Rock.
- Thanks.
- Let's go. That's it.
- Underneath it.
- Hey, Rock.
- What?
- How about an autograph?
Get out of here!
Don't interrupt me
while I'm conducting business.
Move your little chicken asses out.
Hey, listen, kid.
You lay off that pet shop dame.
Women weaken legs.
Yeah, but I really like
this girl, you know?
Then let her train you!
Okay, no more fooling around.
Okay. Now hit it.
Women weaken legs, huh?
- Yo, Rock.
- Yo, Rocky.
You look great.
- Really?
- Oh, yeah.
Terrific.
I mean, you could be a heartbreak.
You'll walk down the street
breaking hearts the way you're looking.
Very sharp.
I got another surprise for you.
What?
Butkus! Hey, Butkus.
Come here, kid.
To keep you company when you run.
Come in and meet the family.
The owner never come back?
Gloria says he's yours
if you want him.
Do I want him? What's he eat?
He eats little turtles.
What's that, Butkus?
Whose truck is this? Come on.
One call from me, you're a celebrity.
You got... Need exposure.
- Don't breathe on me.
- That's the big time.
Don't I know about these things?
You don't know nothing.
What do they want from me?
To watch you train.
What is the matter with you?
This is supposed to be private.
- I'm doing you a favor.
- You ain't doing me no favors!
You're embarrassing me
in front of everybody.
You'll make me look bad
in front of your sis...
See this cigar?
I'm gonna stick it in your ear.
Don't do these things to me.
You should've called me.
Leave a message.
Don't do that.
My sister really likes you.
I'm gonna kill you one
of these days!
Come on.
- Baby!
- Baby.
Here he is, the next heavyweight
champion of the world, Rocky Balboa!
Hello there. Rocky Balboa.
We wanna get a brief
interview with you.
- What about me?
- What about you?
- I'm in charge of the meat.
- Fine. Stand behind it.
Settle yourself down.
Relax.
What we're going to do
is ask you a few questions.
Just a few questions
about your unique training method.
Talk to the folks at home.
They really wanna know
how you got into this.
This isn't an everyday thing.
Jimmy, you guys ready?
Let's roll it.
Rocky, turn around here.
Just don't take no
cheap shots, you know?
No, I won't do that.
Just relax.
Today we're here with
heavyweight challenger Rocky Balboa.
The reason we're standing in this...
The meat guy's sticking his face in.
Let's try it again, Rocky.
Today we 're here with
heavyweight challenger Rocky Balboa.
The reason we 're standing
in this refrigerated box
is that Mr. Balboa
has an unusual method of training.
In a moment, he'll demonstrate that
for the viewing audience at home.
But first, Rocky, how did you
come to train in an Icebox?
Well, my friend,
the guy over there,
he let me in one day,
and I hit the beef here and liked it,
and since I've become a challenger,
the owner don't mind that I come in.
Is this a common training method?
Do other fighters pound raw meat?
No, I think I invented it.
- Would you give us a demonstration?
- Confirm the reservation
for my people at ringside,
and fly my barber to Philly.
How much is being channeled into
West Coast closed-circuit advertising?
- 300,000.
- Make it 450.
And send the mayor's wife
200 roses from me,
and make sure we get a picture of it
for all the newspapers.
Do you want to run the 15
radio spots in the Midwest?
You can spend your money better
in Canadian publicity.
By the way, Apollo,
I've got friends in Toronto
who can get you a good tax break.
George, I like your friends.
Hey, Champ. You ought to come look at
this boy you're gonna fight on TV.
- Looks like he means business.
- Yeah, I mean business too.
Shirley,
we got any more coffee out there?
Certainly, Mr. Creed.
I'll get you some right away.
After the fight,
I may retire and run for emperor.
Diana Lewis in the meat house
with southpaw Rocky Balboa.
And he called the reporters?
Yeah. Threw my
training schedule off.
Don't be mad at him.
He's trying to help.
Adrian, I ain't mad,
it's just that when reporters are
around, I get out of joint
'cause they take cheap shots,
and Paulie knows that.
And Paulie keeps asking me
for a job all the time
but he don't know nothing
about fighting.
Are you gonna say
anything to him?
What's to say? I just don't
know what he wants from me.
I don't want nothing from you.
This ain't no charity case.
Get out of my house.
It's not just your house.
You're no friend no more.
- Get out of my house, I just says.
- Don't talk to him like that.
Both of you get out of my house!
It's cold outside, Paulie.
I don't want you messing her
and I don't raise you
to go with this scum bum!
Yeah? Come on!
You wanna hit on me?
Come on! I'll break both your arms
so they don't work for you.
Stop it!
I'm not good enough to meet with Gazzo?
That's what I think of Gazzo!
Now you're a big shot fighter, you don't
even throw a crumb to your friend.
When I go and get your meat
every morning!
You forgot that? And then I
even give you my sister too!
- Only a pig would say that!
- I'm a pig?
A pig gets you the best?
You're such a loser!
I don't get married because of you!
You can't live by yourself!
I put you two together,
and don't you forget it!
You owe me!
- You owe me!
- What do I owe you?
You're supposed to be good to me!
What do I owe you, Paulie?
I treat you good!
I cook for you, I clean for you,
I pick up your dirty clothes!
I take care of you, Paulie!
I don't owe you nothing!
And you made me
feel like a loser!
I'm not a loser!
- You're busted!
- What?
You're not a virgin!
You let a man take
down your pants!
She's busted!
I can't haul meat no more!
You want a roommate?
Absolutely.
Okay, now
when you walk into the ring
with the number one
heavyweight of the world
you'll be ready, won't you?
Why? Because I waited for 50 years
to make you ready.
You'll be able to spit nails, kid!
Like the guy says,
you're gonna eat lightning
and you're gonna crap thunder!
You're gonna become
a very dangerous person.
Yo, Mickey.
Hey, how are you? Oh, Rock.
I want you to meet our cut man here.
Al Salvani.
- Take a look at his eye.
- How you doing, Al?
- That's right.
- It ain't bad. Seen worse.
- You ain't so bad yourself.
- Cover up. Things will be okay.
You cover up.
Go and take a shower.
Okay, Mick. I'll see you tomorrow.
You covered that Whitmore fight?
- That's why he won.
- Listen. We got a winner here.
We got a chance. He goes to the body
like nobody you've ever seen.
You just stand by. We're gonna win.
Hey, Rock. It's okay I talk to you?
Okay you talk to me? Sure.
I figured some angle
to make some money off your name.
My name? How's that?
Advertising.
I know about that stuff.
What do you know about advertising?
Hey, you can make money off my name,
make it, okay?
I'm gonna take a shower.
- Wanna help me off with these?
- Sure.
You're gonna kill him!
Rocky. What brings you here tonight?
Mr. Jergens, the poster's wrong.
What do you mean?
I'm wearing white pants
with a red stripe.
It doesn't really matter, does it?
I'm sure you're gonna give us
a great show.
Try to get some rest, kid.
Good night.
I can't do it.
What?
I can't beat him.
Apollo?
Yeah.
I been out there, walking
around, thinking.
Who am I kidding?
I ain't even in the guy's league.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
You worked so hard.
Yeah, it don't matter,
'cause I was nobody before.
Don't say that.
Oh, come on, Adrian. It's true.
I was nobody.
But that don't matter
either, you know?
'Cause I was thinking,
it really don't matter
if I lose this fight.
It really don't matter
if this guy opens my head either.
'Cause all I wanna do
is go the distance.
Nobody's ever gone the distance
with Creed,
and if I can go that distance,
and that bell rings,
and I'm still standing,
I'm gonna know
for the first time in my life, see,
that I weren't just another bum
from the neighborhood.
Time, kid. Let's go.
I'll wait for you here.
How about I wait here
and you fight, huh?
You're looking very great today,
you know that?
I gotta go now,
but don't you leave town, huh?
Wish me luck. I'm gonna need it.
Good luck.
Adrian, you don't think
this robe is too baggy, huh?
Good luck.
Don't leave town.
I'd like you to meet
my colleague, Stu Nahan.
Thank you, Bill Baldwin.
The electricity is all over the
place tonight, as Rocky Balboa...
What is that?
I trained you to be a fighter,
not a billboard.
- I'm doing it for a friend.
- What do you get out of it?
Paulie gets $3,000. I get the robe.
Shrewd.
The story about tonight's fight,
their difference in style,
you can quote
a recent sports magazine which said,
it could be
"the caveman against the cavalier."
I notice a buzzing
in the background.
Could be the challenger is getting
ready to get into the ring.
Rocky, look at my date.
- Cost me $200.
- $250.
I gotta go. I gotta work.
- How's the robe?
- A little baggy.
A 50-to-1 underdog
living a Cinderella story,
and he's captured people's
imaginations all over the world.
We love you, Rocky!
- Good luck, champ.
- Thanks for showing up.
And his record, 44 victories.
He's had 38 by knockout,
and he's lost 20 fights.
Which makes me wonder,
can he stand it?
You know, the stamina and the skill
to last three rounds.
Because Las Vegas odds say no.
Rocky Balboa,
climbing into the ring now.
"The Italian Stallion."
Some meat sign on the back of his robe.
You seen what that was?
Shamrock Meat...
There's a lot of noise
coming from the background.
- They have spotlights.
- I see right back there.
Is that the world heavyweight
champion, Apollo Creed?
He's riding in a boat. Is he
supposed to be George Washington?
Obviously so.
He's got the hat on, the whole thing.
The world champion, Apollo Creed
is doing an imitation
of George Washington.
He's throwing money.
Remember when we were growing up,
we were taught about George Washington
throwing a dollar.
If you threw a dollar in those days,
it went a lot farther.
Now he's taking his...
Blonde wig came off.
The hat came off.
I want you!
The crowd is loving
every minute of it.
- Here is the world heavyweight champion.
- Apollo Creed.
For you around the world
he was dressed as George Washington,
the father of our country.
I want you!
I don't believe what I'm seeing.
Uncle Sam himself!
I want you!
I want all of you!
He looks like a big flag.
I want you!
- Is he talking to me?
- He's talking to you.
- Let him talk.
I want the Stallion!
He says, "I want the Stallion."
For you in foreign countries,
during World War I,
the picture of Uncle Sam
with his finger pointed like that
was a recruiting poster
for our fellows in the service,
the army and the navy.
"I want you."
That's what he's doing a take on.
He's yelling, "Creed in three."
What do you think
that outfit cost?
Ladies and gentlemen.
Good evening.
A very Happy New Year.
Welcome to Philadelphia.
Everybody who's anybody
is here tonight.
Time does not
permit me to introduce
the many luminaries of politics,
show business and the sporting world
who are with us tonight
but I would like to present
one of the immortals of pugilism,
a champion in and out of the ring,
Philadelphia's own "Smoking Joe,"
the beloved Mr. Joe Frazier!
How you doing?
Don't hurt him, okay?
I'll try not to.
What a credit he's been
in his career as a fighter
Now he's coming over
to talk to the champ.
- Hey, Joe.
- You been ducking me a long time.
No, Joe. You're next.
- You're next.
- You understand?
They must be friends.
Joe Frazier!
- Fight fans, get settled down.
- Go home!
- Don't stay in the arena!
- It won't be long now.
Now for the main event.
On my left
the challenger, in white trunks,
weighing 190 pounds.
Philadelphia's favorite son,
The Italian Stallion,
Rocky Balboa.
And on my right
wearing red, white and blue,
weighing 210 pounds,
undefeated in 46 fights,
The Master of Disaster,
the undisputed heavyweight champion
of the world,
Apollo Creed!
I want you! You!
You, chump. I want you!
You've both fought in
Philadelphia before. You know the rules.
No low blows,
watch your heads, no butting.
Shake hands and come out fighting.
Put your hands up there, chump.
- Come out fighting.
- Come on!
Rocky's just going over and
being calm, it looks like from here.
There goes the big hat.
I've never seen a fighter
that concerned about his hair.
There's the bell for round one.
The fighters come in the center of
the ring, looking at each other.
Creed, the champion,
zipping in those left-handed jabs.
Right there. Bang.
The champ stinging the slower
challenger with jabs at will.
In fact, it looks like Rocky
is blocking the blows with his face.
The champion doesn't look the best
he's ever been, but he's moving now.
The champion's smiling now.
He's toying with him.
Trying to give the fans
their money's worth.
He's very clearly outclassed
the challenger right now.
He's trying to make his
man miss like that.
The champ is just taunting him.
Creed dancing around.
I don't believe this!
The champ is down!
Creed is down!
What a surprise this is!
This is the first time the champion
has ever been knocked down.
The referee is giving
him the count.
Six, seven, eight.
He appears to be all right.
Glassy-eyed but okay.
Go to the ribs!
Go to work, Rock!
Come on!
Rocky coming back out, and he's
like a bull in a china closet.
He really wants it.
Apollo, left to the head.
The champion's coming off the floor
and he's trying to put him away.
A left, a right.
Combinations into the face!
That's the Apollo we know.
Now the champ is taunting Rocky
to come and get some more.
A left. Another.
Another left.
Rocky's coming back!
Rocky's got him on the ropes!
Let's break it.
You're holding.
You're posing as a boxer.
There's no way we expected
this kind of hitting.
Apollo unloading a left.
He's got him up against the ropes.
They're leading him to his corner.
Rocky can't find his way.
I called it!
- Your nose is broke.
- How's it look?
It's an improvement.
Quit shucking and jiving!
Stick and move!
Go for the ribs.
Don't let that bastard breathe.
The guy's quick.
He doesn't know it's a damn show.
He thinks it's a damn fight.
Finish this bum, and let's go home.
Stay to the body.
You're doing great!
Round two. Creed predicted
he'd win it in three.
Creed got knocked down in the first.
He came back strong.
He's working hard.
A sharp left.
Again, a hard right.
Now coming in.
He's knocked him into the corner again.
The champion's got him
backed into the corner.
Pummeling him left and right,
his head bouncing against the ropes.
Balboa's taking
a tremendous beating here.
Battering him like a punching bag.
What's keeping him up?
Can't you fight?
Stop clowning around
and give the people something!
- Come on!
- He says he wants more!
He wants more. You folks
watching television around the world
you're watching a battle.
Balboa trying to fight back.
Oh, he tagged the champ!
The champion is trying to get out
of there, but he can't do it.
He is being barraged with lefts
and rights to the head and body.
Balboa is tagging the champion
right on the kisser!
The referee steps in.
They're ready to keep going.
Back to your corners!
Come on, Creed!
This is gonna be a tough one.
- Back with a left!
- He got tagged!
The referee's wiping
off the gloves.
Hard left and right
combination!
- What is keeping him up, Bill?
- I don't know.
He can't even get his gloves up
to protect himself.
Down! Stay down!
Apollo has his arms in the air!
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Come on!
Apollo can't believe it.
The champion got a left
to his right ribs.
This has been a tremendous...
Okay, champ?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I may have broke my ribs.
I can't see nothing.
Gotta open my eye.
- Cut me.
- Don't wanna do it.
- Go ahead. Cut me.
- Okay.
Try it. Cut it.
Creed! Creed!
Oh, God.
You're bleeding inside.
I'm gonna stop the fight.
You ain't stopping
nothing, man.
You stop this fight,
I'll kill you!
- I'm going.
- If you wanna go.
You gotta give it all!
You gotta get him!
The 15th and final round.
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
They look like they've been in a war.
A hard right.
The champion really tagged him.
Apollo clearly protecting
his right side, his ribs.
Body punches!
Hard lefts and rights. Look at the
blood coming out of his mouth!
He's spitting up blood now.
A tremendous right hand by Rocky.
Go for it, Rock!
- Listen to this crowd!
- Right to the ribs.
Another to the ribs.
That left hand again.
Right to the jaw!
He's got him up against the ropes!
Apollo the champ...
Ain't gonna be no rematch.
Don't want one.
Rocky, you went the distance,
15 rounds. How do you feel?
- All right.
- What were you thinking about...
- Adrian!
- ...coming out for the 15th round?
Adrian!
Rocky!
- Tonight...
- Rocky!
...we have had the
privilege of witnessing
the greatest exhibition
of boxing stamina
in the history of the ring.
Adrian!
Rocky!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a split decision.
Judge Walker
for Creed!
Adrian!
- Your fans want a rematch.
- Ain't gonna be no rematch!
- Adrian!
- You heard him...
- You can't go in there!
- That's my friend. Let go!
- You're wrecking the jacket!
- Rocky!
- Paulie.
- Adrian!
I love you!
- I love you!